Leeam Shutzman

Software Developer

ABOUT ME

I am a software developer currently working at Cognizant. In my current role, I focus on backend development using Java and Spring. I also have experience developing backends using Node.js. During college, I developed several Java-based Android apps as well as a full-stack web app, all of which can be seen on my website.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Java, C++, JavaScript
- Microservices (REST APIs, MVC)
- Spring
- · Spring Boot
- Thymeleaf
- Kafka (Java, Spring, CLI)
- SQL (MySQL, Microsoft, Oracle)
- NoSQL(MongoDB, Mongoose)
- Plaid API
- · Apache Avro
- Android (Java, XML)
- Docker (docker-compose, Docker)
- Web Development (HTML, CSS, JS, Express, Node.js)
- Git/GitHub
- Apigee
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CCP)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Portfolio: https://leeamshutzman.github.io/

Work Tracker 2021

 Simplifies tracking freelance work hours by utilizing a mobile app, a website, an SQL database, a Node.js server, Express, and EJS

Cool Guy App 2021

- Streak keeping Android app for how many days in a row the user has been productive
- Utilizes daily notifications to prompt the user

Professor Rating App 2020

- Android based app for rating professors within Webster University
- Google Firebase Realtime Database Movie Kiosk

Oracle APEX Application 2020

- Year long project for Database Concepts/Applications class
- Designed and implemented relational database schema

Paperless Parking Ticketing System 2019 - 2020

- Semester project for System Analysis and Design class
- Analyzed current ticketing system at Webster University and designed new paperless system
- Android based QR code scanner prototype.

LeeamShutzman@gmail.com <u>My Website</u> <u>My GitHub</u>

WORK HISTORY

Digital Technology Developer

Cognizant

January 2022 - Present

- Designed and developed a band mate finding web app that uses REST API endpoints to serve static resources such as audio files and photos.
- Developed RESTful Microservices for an e-commerce app using Spring Boot, a Eureka service registry, an API cloud gateway, a Cloud config server, a MySQL database, and Kafka messaging.
- Implemented the CQRS pattern with Event-sourcing using Spring boot while using Kafka as the event store and a MongoDB NoSQL database for read operations. Records were sent using a specific Avro schema

Independent Contractor

Private Customer

June 2020 - July 2020

 Full basement renovation. Tasks included drywall, floor instalation, painting, design and construction of a stage, a wall mounted wine rack, and a bar with a live edge slab top

Chess Summer Camp Counselor

Webster University

June 2017 - July 2019

- Assisted in keeping children safe between and during various activities
- Transported and distributed required materials
- Daily meetings to discuss issues and ways to improve the experience for both the staff and the campers

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelors of Science: Computer Science

Webster University - St. Louis, MO

2018 - 2021

- · Minored in Math
- Represented Webster at International Collegiate Programing Contest 2019
- Represented Webster at CHECC CyberCup 2019
- Represented Webster at Deloitte Capture the Flag Competition 2019

Languages

- English (Native)
- Spanish (Fluent)
- Hungarian (Fluent)
- Hebrew (Intermediate)